<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home on leroyer.io</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in home on leroyer.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Improving network latency of DaemonSet in Kubernetes with Internal Traffic Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-27-improving-network-latency-of-daemonset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-10-27-improving-network-latency-of-daemonset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At our company, we primarily operate on bare-metal infrastructure, which provides us with very low network&#xA;latency within a zone or datacenter. When we began migrating services to Kubernetes (also running on bare-metal),&#xA;we needed to ensure that certain daemons running on each bare-metal server were also present on Kubernetes nodes&#xA;in a Kubernetes-native manner. To achieve this, we utilized DaemonSets, which are designed for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will focus on a specific service we use, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/mcrouter&#34;&gt;mcrouter&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;a proxy that enhances &lt;a href=&#34;https://memcached.org/&#34;&gt;memcached&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s reliability by facilitating read/write operations to&#xA;multiple memcached servers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using HAProxy to act as an HTTP server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-11-13-using-haproxy-as-an-http-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 17:54:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022-11-13-using-haproxy-as-an-http-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my work, I stumbled upon some little problems that often require to deploy several component for just a simple task.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, we had to validate with our CDN that our endpoint was own by us. Fair enough, let&amp;rsquo;s set a TXT record on our DNS servers! Well, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t always work that way. Those providers required an HTTP validation with a specific URL and content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have two providers requesting an HTTP endpoint with a specific url/content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Output Kafka Logs to Syslog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-05-26-output-kafka-logs-to-syslog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 23:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-05-26-output-kafka-logs-to-syslog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been strugling with Kafka recently, or at least log4j.&#xA;The default configuration output a lot of logs to stdout. In my actual configuration, stdout logs from an application are captured by systemd-journald and then given to rsyslog.&#xA;This can come handy when the application doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to log with syslog.&#xA;However, I had an issue with Kafka and journald where logs were also written to the filesystem until the partition is full.&#xA;So output log directly to rsyslog was necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-12-23-starting-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 19:16:51 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-12-23-starting-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So it begins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting a blog and I will try to write some posts related to tech stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of my posts will be about opensource stuff related to infrastructure and linux systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope that you will enjoy reading my posts!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the mean time you can check links in the sidebar and come back here in a few months :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In IT for at least 10 years, I&amp;rsquo;m a passionate engineer that can be quickly interested in anything.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Typical geek/nerd: I like IT, video games, music, mangas and animes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;career-summary&#34;&gt;Career summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started working as an apprentice at Netvibes in 2013 as a System Administrator. I made a short hop into a big company (EDF) as a Developper from 2013 to 2016, still as an apprentice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After being graduate from CNAM Engineering School, I got my first job as a System Administrator at Deezer in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
